## Huai, Shuo Ph.D. Candidate

I received the BSc degree from the School of Computer Science and Technology, Shandong University, Jinan, China, in 2019. I am currently pursuing the Ph.D. degree with the School of Computer Science and Engineering, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore. My research interests are embedded intelligence, neural network optimization, in-memory computing, and non-volatile memory.



## **Education**

Jan. 2020 – Present Ph.D., Nanyang Technological University
Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering Supervisor: Prof. Liu Weichen

Sep. 2015 – Jun. 2019

BSc, Shandong University

Bachelor of Computer Science and Technology

Advisor: Prof. Zhao Mengying

## **Research Publications**

### **Conference Proceedings**

- H. Chen, D. Liu, S. Li, **S. Huai**, X. Luo, and W. Liu, "Mugnoc: A software-configured multicast-unicast-gather noc for accelerating cnn dataflows," in *Proceedings of the 28th Asia and South Pacific Design Automation Conference*, 2023, pp. 308–313.
- **S. Huai**, D. Liu, X. Luo, H. Chen, W. Liu, and R. Subramaniam, "Crossbar-aligned & integer-only neural network compression for efficient in-memory acceleration," in *Proceedings of the 28th Asia and South Pacific Design Automation Conference*, 2023, pp. 234–239.
- H. Kong, X. Luo, **S. Huai**, et al., "Emnape: Efficient multi-dimensional neural architecture pruning for edgeai," in 2023 Design, Automation & Test in Europe Conference & Exhibition (DATE), IEEE, 2023, pp. 1–2.
- **S. Huai**, D. Liu, H. Kong, *et al.*, "Collate: Collaborative neural network learning for latency-critical edge systems," in 2022 IEEE 40th International Conference on Computer Design (ICCD), IEEE, 2022, pp. 627–634.
- H. Kong, D. Liu, **S. Huai**, et al., "Smart scissor: Coupling spatial redundancy reduction and cnn compression for embedded hardware," in *Proceedings of the 41st IEEE/ACM International Conference on Computer-Aided Design*, 2022, pp. 1–9.
- X. Luo, D. Liu, H. Kong, **S. Huai**, H. Chen, and W. Liu, "Work-in-progress: What to expect of early training statistics? an investigation on hardware-aware neural architecture search," in 2022 International Conference on Hardware/Software Codesign and System Synthesis (CODES+ ISSS), IEEE, 2022, pp. 1–2.
- X. Luo, D. Liu, H. Kong, **S. Huai**, H. Chen, and W. Liu, "You only search once: On lightweight differentiable architecture search for resource-constrained embedded platforms," in *Proceedings of the 59th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference*, 2022, pp. 475–480.
- **S. Huai**, L. Zhang, D. Liu, W. Liu, and R. Subramaniam, "Zerobn: Learning compact neural networks for latency-critical edge systems," in 2021 58th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC), IEEE, 2021, pp. 151–156.
- X. Luo, D. Liu, **S. Huai**, and W. Liu, "Hsconas: Hardware-software co-design of efficient dnns via neural architecture search," in 2021 Design, Automation & Test in Europe Conference & Exhibition (DATE), IEEE, 2021, pp. 418–421.
- **S. Huai**, W. Song, M. Zhao, X. Cai, and Z. Jia, "Performance-aware wear leveling for block ram in nonvolatile fpgas," in *Proceedings of the 56th Annual Design Automation Conference 2019*, 2019, pp. 1–6.

## **Journal Articles**

**S. Huai**, H. Kong, S. Li, *et al.*, "Evolp: Self-evolving latency predictor for model compression in real-time edge systems," *IEEE Embedded Systems Letters*, 2023.

- **S. Huai**, H. Kong, X. Luo, *et al.*, "Crimp: Compact & reliable dnns inference for in-memory processing via crossbar-aligned compression and non-ideality adaptation," *ACM Transactions on Embedded Computing Systems*, 2023.
- **S. Huai**, H. Kong, X. Luo, *et al.*, "On hardware-aware design and optimization of edge intelligence," *IEEE Design & Test*, 2023.
- **S. Huai**, D. Liu, H. Kong, *et al.*, "Latency-constrained dnn architecture learning for edge systems using zerorized batch normalization," *Future Generation Computer Systems*, vol. 142, pp. 314–327, 2023.
- H. Kong, D. Liu, **S. Huai**, et al., "Edgecompress: Coupling multi-dimensional model compression and dynamic inference for edgeai," *IEEE Transactions on Computer-Aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems*, 2023.
- 6 S. Li, **S. Huai**, and W. Liu, "An efficient gustavson-based sparse matrix-matrix multiplication accelerator on embedded fpgas," *IEEE Transactions on Computer-Aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems*, 2023.
- H. Chen, P. Chen, X. Luo, **S. Huai**, and W. Liu, "Lamp: Load-balanced multipath parallel transmission in point-to-point nocs," *IEEE Transactions on Computer-Aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems*, vol. 41, no. 12, pp. 5232–5245, 2022.
- X. Luo, D. Liu, H. Kong, **S. Huai**, H. Chen, and W. Liu, "Lightnas: On lightweight and scalable neural architecture search for embedded platforms," *IEEE Transactions on Computer-Aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems*, 2022.
- X. Luo, D. Liu, H. Kong, **S. Huai**, H. Chen, and W. Liu, "Surgenas: A comprehensive surgery on hardware-aware differentiable neural architecture search," *IEEE Transactions on Computers*, vol. 72, no. 4, pp. 1081–1094, 2022.
- H. Kong, **S. Huai**, D. Liu, *et al.*, "Edlab: A benchmark for edge deep learning accelerators," *IEEE Design & Test*, vol. 39, no. 3, pp. 8−17, 2021.
- X. Luo, D. Liu, **S. Huai**, H. Kong, H. Chen, and W. Liu, "Designing efficient dnns via hardware-aware neural architecture search and beyond," *IEEE Transactions on Computer-Aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems*, vol. 41, no. 6, pp. 1799–1812, 2021.

### **Experience**

#### Work

Sep. 2019 - Oct. 2023

■ Project Officer, HP-NTU Digital Manufacturing Corporate Lab

Machine Learning Optimization for Edge Devices

- Design a performance evaluation methodology and toolset for Machine Learning Accelerators.
- Provide HP business groups, like Business Personal Systems and Digital Manufacturing, the insights, and framework for process and resource-efficient design and optimization of DNN, accelerators, and system architectures for machine learning/inference at the edge.

#### **Teaching**

Feb. 2020 - Mar. 2020

■ Teaching Assistant, Nanyang Technological University CE/CZ 1006 Computer Organisation & Architecture

Feb. 2019 - Jun. 2019

■ Teaching Assistant, Shandong University
SD01331470 Computer Organization and Design

### **Awards and Achievements**

- 2023 **Support Grant**, ACM SIGDA Student Research Forum, ASP-DAC 2023, Japan.
- 2019 **Quistanding Undergraduate Graduation Dissertation**, Shandong University.
- 2018 DAC system Design Contest (6/61).
- 2017 Meritorious Winner, COMAP's Mathematical Contest In Modeling.

## **Innovations**

#### **Patent**

# A Non-Volatile FPGA Placement Optimization Method and System Based on Performance-aware Wear Leveling

Inventors: 1) Zhao Mengying; 2) Huai Shuo; 3) Shen Zhaoyan; 4) Cai Xiaojun; 5) Jia Zhiping

Filed date: 20 May 2019

Patent No.: ZL 2019 1 0419760.9

#### **Technology Disclosure (TD)**

#### ■ EDLAB: A Benchmark Tool for Edge Deep Learning Accelerators

Inventors: 1) Liu Weichen; 2) Liu Di; 3) Kong Hao; 4) Zhang Lei; 5) Huai Shuo; 6) Li Shiqing; 7) Chen Hui; 8)

Zhu Shien

Filed date: 08 July 2020 Ref: TD 2020-264

#### **▼** ZeroBN: Learning Compact Neural Networks For Latency-Critical Edge Systems

Inventors: 1) Liu Weichen; 2) **Huai Shuo**; 3) Liu Di; 4) Zhang Lei

Filed date: 09 March 2021

Ref: TD 2021-096

#### Collaborative Neural Network Learning For Multiple Latency-Critical Edge Systems

Inventors: 1) Liu Weichen; 2) Huai Shuo; 3) Kong Hao

Filed date: 15 August 2022

Ref: TD 2022-287

# Smart Scissor: A Deep Compression Framework For Jointly Reducing the Redundancy In Images And Neural Networks

Inventors: 1) Liu Weichen; 2) Kong Hao; 3) Huai Shuo

Filed date: 15 August 2022

Ref: TD 2022-288

## **Skills**

Languages Professional working proficiency in English, and native proficiency in Mandarin Chinese.

Coding & OS Python, Java, C/C++, Linux, SQL, Land Verilog